themusicalcompany.com 2019-04-21

# Privacy Policy - The Musical Company

**Last updated: May 24, 2018**

The Musical Company, LP  (“TMC,” “we,” “us” and “our”) cares about your privacy. To better protect your privacy, this notice, together with our Terms and Conditions of Use, explains our policies for the collection and use of personal information we collect from you or you provide to us through our websites, emails and mobile apps (“Sites”). Personal information is information that identifies you as an individual, such as your name, address, email address, or telephone number. Information collected on the Sites may be used in the manner described below by TMC, our labels, our publishing companies, agents, subsidiaries, trusted partners and affiliates acting on our behalf. By visiting this website, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy which may be amended from time to time.    

## **WHAT INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

Our Sites collect information from you when you register with us as part of your participation in our online  license and perusal ordering, newsletter, title updates, promotions, contests or sweepstakes. As part of your registration, we may request the following personally identifiable information: name, organization name, organization type and size, address, mailing address, email address, telephone number, birth date, demographic information (such as country and gender), information about proposed performances (such as audience size, dates, ticket prices and actor salaries), social media profiles, and profile data (such as your music preferences and entertainment practices). If you choose to peruse or license any of our titles, we will collect the following additional personally identifiable information in order to process your transaction:  credit card number or other payment information and billing address. We may also collect your purchase, site browsing and transaction history. Additionally, you may choose to register a website user name and/or password so that we can communicate with you, provide the services you have requested and to provide a more personalized experience on our website. You are not required to provide us with this information, but if you choose not to do so, you may not be able to participate in some of the activities on our Sites. 

We may also offer you the choice of whether to receive mailings from others that we think will be of interest.   In order to keep you informed about the operation of our services, we may also send emails and announcements that are needed for the proper functioning and administration of our Sites and services. Additionally, we have features allowing you to submit information to us (such as when contacting us with a question or feedback).  

We will also collect information about your computer as you browse our Sites. Please see TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES below.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our rights.  

## **TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES**

Our Sites have features that automatically collect information from you to assist us in creating Sites that honor your preferences and serve your needs, allow us to improve our Sites and provide you with tailored advertising.  In certain instances, our Sites use cookies, which are small data files containing information about you that are stored on your hard drive.  Cookies are embedded in the HTTP information that travels back and forth between your computer and the servers. Cookies allow automated customer customization and personalization, and, for example, cookies may be utilized to assure that a sweepstakes applicant enters any given sweepstakes only once or to store session preferences.  We use the following types of cookies on our Sites: 

**Strictly necessary cookies**. These cookies are essential for the operation of our Sites and include, for example, cookies that enable you to browse our website and use its features and to maintain secure areas of our Sites.

**Analytical/performance cookies.** These cookies collect anonymous information about how you use our Sites for example how you arrived at our Sites and which pages you visit most often. This helps us to improve the way our Sites work, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily. These cookies are sometimes placed by third-party providers of web traffic analysis services, such as Google Analytics.

**Functionality cookies.** These are used to recognize you when you return to our Sites in order to improve your experience on our Sites, allowing us to personalize our content for you. 

**Targeting cookies.** These cookies record your visit to our Sites, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. These cookies are usually placed by third-party advertising networks. They remember the other websites you visit, and this information is shared with third-party organizations, for example advertisers. 

**Social Media cookies.** These cookies allow you to share what you’ve been doing on our Sites with social media organizations such as Facebook and Twitter. These cookies are not within our control. Please refer to the privacy policies of these organizations for how their cookies work. 

Most internet browsers are automatically set up to accept cookies. However, if you want to refuse or delete any cookies (or similar technologies), please refer to the help and support area on your internet browser for instructions on how to block or delete cookies. Please note you may not be able to take advantage of all the features of our Sites, if you delete or disable cookies.

**Web Beacons.  **We, or our third party partners, may employ a software technology called web beacons (also known as web bugs, clear gifs or pixels) which helps us understand what content is effective, for example by counting the number of users who have visited these pages, and to understand usage patterns. Web beacons are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to let us know when content is viewed. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, web beacons are embedded on web pages, ads, and e-mail. We, or our third-party partners, may tie the information gathered by web beacons to the other information we collect about you. 

In addition to automatically collecting information from you, our Sites may also access, but not collect, additional information from you (such as browser header information, browser type and IP address) in order to customize your website experience.

## **HOW YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE USED**

We and our trusted partners use the information collected from you to allow you to participate in the website activities for which the information is collected.  For example, when you provide an email address in order to receive updates on a particular title or type of show, that address is added to the email list for that title or type of show. We sometimes use the information collected to communicate with you, such as: to notify you when we make changes to our subscriber agreements; to fulfill your request for an online newsletter; fulfill your order and respond to your customer requests, questions and concerns; administer promotions, contests and sweepstakes; and to contact you about your account with us. From time to time, we may also use this information to offer products, programs or services to our customers. When we have co-branded or sponsored services, when we host a site or when we join with other parties to provide specific services, we may share (provide and/or receive) your personally identifiable information with them. We may also share your information with others if you choose to let us do so, such as where we offer opt-in or opt-out choices. We may share aggregate information (such as demographic data and/or geographic location of users), which is not personally identifiable, with others and in order to improve our services for marketing and/or industry reporting purposes. Such information will not include personally identifiable information such as your name or email address. Aggregate information collected about the users of our website may also be used to improve our services, for marketing purposes and industry reporting purposes. Additionally, we may share your personally identifiable information in the event of a corporate change (such as a merger, acquisition or sale of assets). 

Other than as set forth in this privacy policy, we do not share your personally identifiable information with other companies, apart from those acting as our agents in providing services to you and which agree to use it only for that purpose and to keep the information secure and confidential.  We will also disclose information we maintain (i) when required to do so by law (for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena or other legal obligation), (ii) in response to a law enforcement agency’s request, or (iii) in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with our rights or property. 

We may combine information we receive from other sources with information you give to us and information we collect about you (including information in relation to your devices). We may use this combined information for the purposes set out above.  

## **PROMOTIONS, CONTESTS AND SWEEPSTAKES**

When you enter or participate in one of our promotions, contests or sweepstakes, we will request information from you (such as your name, address, phone number, birthdate and email address) and we may also request demographic or profile information. All promotions, contests and sweepstakes that are held on this website are limited to persons above a certain age. If the birth date provided indicates that you are underage, the information submitted will be deleted.  We will use the information you provide for the purpose of conducting the promotion, contest or sweepstakes (for example, to contact you if you have won). We may sometimes partner with sponsors in offering a promotion, contest or sweepstakes and we may share your information with them.  For further information about how we handle your personally identifiable information when you enter one of our promotions, contests or sweepstakes, please consult the applicable promotion, contest or sweepstakes rules. 

## **WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION**

The information we collect from you may be transferred to, stored, used and processed by entities around the world as described in this privacy policy. We will take steps to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. By submitting personally identifiable information, you agree to the collection, transfer, storage and use of your information as described in this policy. 

## **LINKS TO THIRD PARTY WEBSITES AND THE INTERNET**

Our Sites may contain links to third party websites. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these website have their own privacy policies and we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check the policies before you submit any personally identifiable information to these websites. 

The transmission of information over the internet is not completely secure.  If you provide us with information over the internet, any transmission is at your own risk. However, once we receive your information, we use commercially reasonable procedures and security to prevent unauthorized access to personally identifiable information about you.

## **OPT-IN/OPT-OUT CHOICE**

Our website may provide you with the opportunity to choose to receive communications from us or from third parties at the point where we request information about you. You have the option of removing your name from any email list.  In order to ensure the quickest removal from any list, it is best to follow the specific instructions with the communications you receive from us.

## **CHILDREN**

We strive to comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act. We do not knowingly collect any personal information from those under the age of 13. If you are under 13 years of age, please do not provide any personal information to us. If you feel that we have unknowingly collected personal information from someone under the age of 13, please contact us immediately as described in the CONTACT US section below and this information will be removed. For more information on how to protect your children online: Visit [www.OnGuardOnline.gov](https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/features/feature-0038-onguardonline) for social networking safety tips for parents and youth.

## **YOUR RIGHTS**

You may be entitled, in accordance with applicable law, to object to or request the restriction of processing of your personal information, and to request access to, rectification, erasure, and portability of your own personal information by contacting us as described in the CONTACT US section below. We may require you to prove your identity with approved identification if you request this information.

You may also be entitled, in accordance with applicable law, to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes applicable law.

You are responsible for keeping your information current and up-to-date. You may update your information by contacting us as described in the CONTACT US section below.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter, we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or you can contact us as described in the CONTACT US section below.

## **YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

If you are a California resident, California Civil Code 1798.83 provides you the right to receive (a) information identifying any third party to whom we may have disclosed, with the preceding calendar year, your personally identifiable information for that third party’s direct marketing purposes and (b) a description of the categories of personally identifiable information disclosed.  To obtain such information free of charge, please write to us at the address below or submit your request to legal@themusicalcompany.com .  

## **CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

We reserve the right to modify, alter or otherwise update this privacy policy at any time.   We encourage you to review this policy from time to time to be informed about how we protect your information.   When we post changes to this policy, you will see the word “last updated” with the date of the last update at the top of this page.  

## **USERS OF SITES IN THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA**

This section of this privacy policy applies only if you use the Sites from a country that is a Member State of the European Economic Area and supplements the information in this privacy policy.

**Legal Basis for Data Processing:** We process personal information for the purposes set out in this privacy policy, as described above. Our legal basis to process personal information includes processing that is: necessary for the performance of the contract between you and us (for example, to provide you with the services you request and to identify and authenticate you so you may use the Sites); necessary to comply with legal requirements (for example, to comply with applicable accounting rules and to make mandatory disclosures to law enforcement); necessary for our legitimate interests (for example, to manage our relationship with you and to improve the Sites); and based on consent by our customers (for example, to communicate with you about our products and services and provide you with marketing information), which may subsequently be withdrawn at any time (by using preference settings in emails or on our Sites or emailing us as set out in the CONTACT US section below) without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.

We may use automated decision-making technologies, including profiling, to support our data processing activities. Our automated decision-making capabilities include logic that attempts to identify artists, music, communications, products, or offers that we believe may interest you. By using this logic, it helps us personalize your interactions with us and our artists. For you, this means that you may see online advertisements, direct marketing communications (if you have subscribed), or other advertising or marketing messages or special offers based on your activity on our Sites or interactions with us or our third-party partners.

In some instances, you may be required to provide us with personal information for processing as described above, in order for us to be able to provide you the ability to use all the features of the Sites.

**International transfers:** Our sharing of your personal information, in accordance with this privacy policy, may involve transferring your information outside the European Economic Area (EEA). Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring, where required by law, at least one of the following safeguards is implemented: transferring personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission; using specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe; or transferring personal data to the United States to an entity if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US.

You may be entitled, in accordance with applicable law, to request a copy of relevant safeguards by contacting us as described in the CONTACT US section.

## **COMMUNITY FUNCTIONS**

Our website may make available to you chat rooms, forums, message boards and/or other community functions.  Remember that any information you disclose in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal, financial or other information.   Your use of such community functions is at your own risk.

## **CONTACT US**

If you have questions regarding this privacy policy, please contact us at The Musical Company, LP, 214 Sullivan Street, Ste 4, New York, NY 10012, Attn: Legal Department or email us at [legal@themusicalcompany.com](mailto:legal@themusicalcompany.com).
